<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Icarus</title>
    <description>My thoughts on books</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 17:48:03 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 17:48:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blitzscaling: The Lightning-Fast Path to Building Massively Valuable Companies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just finished reading this book! Review coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blitzscaling/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blitzscaling/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trillion Dollar Coach</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As an individual in the tech industry, the story of Bill Campbell, Silicon Valley’s Coach is really one that I should have heard of a long time ago. The sheer fact that I did not, really goes to show that Coach didn’t like to be in the public limelight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book shines a light on how one man and his teachings were behind the successes of so many tech CEO’s and teams in Silicon Valley. The title is apt in the fact that the people he helped included Steve Jobs, Eric Schmidt, Larry Page, Sergey Brin that among just people from 2 companies (Apple and Google) the valuation exceeds a trillion dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book narrates the story of how this football coach turned tech coach influenced the career paths of so many. Although he was a great football coach, he was often looked down upon for caring about his athlete’s overall performance in school as well as their athletics but he was able to use apply this holistic approach of training to mentoring tech leaders in their conquests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book offers troves of advice on how to mentor people on your teams, foster their growth all while establishing trusting relationships. Bill Campbell was able to apply his techniques on such a large scale and in such an effective manner that the legacy he left behind still carries weight among the Silicon Valley elites that came together to write this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this book to be very helpful if I were to ever find myself in the position of mentoring someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some selected quotes that I loved from the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the people who showed up to Bill’s memorial
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;So there was no way Bruno &lt;em&gt;[Bill’s regular caddie]&lt;/em&gt; was going to miss Bill’s memorial. When he arrived at Sacred Heart that afternoon, he was ushered toward the front, close to Bill’s family. “I was sitting right behind Mr. Cook and Eddy Cue, from Apple,” he says. “And right next to a guy, I forget his name. I think he runs Google.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On profanity in the workplace
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bill was a delightfully profane man. He used the F-word the way people today uselike, almost as if it’s a new part of speech, not verb, adverb, adjective, pronoun, or noun, but a word of its own category. Jonathan once sent Bill a study he had found showing that swearing in the workplace enhances morale. Bill’s uncharacteristically understated response: “A good one for me!”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On leadership
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“your title makes you a manager; your people make you a leader.”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Trust means freeing people to do their jobs and to make decisions. It means knowing people want to do well and believing that they will.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEAD BASED ON FIRST PRINCIPLES&lt;/strong&gt;:  DEFINE THE “FIRST PRINCIPLES” FOR THE SITUATION, THE IMMUTABLE TRUTHS THAT ARE THE FOUNDATION FOR THE COMPANY OR PRODUCT, AND HELP GUIDE THE DECISION FROM THOSE PRINCIPLES.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MANAGE THE ABERRANT GENIUS ABERRANT&lt;/strong&gt;: GENIUSES—HIGH-PERFORMING BUT DIFFICULT TEAM MEMBERS—SHOULD BE TOLERATED AND EVEN PROTECTED, AS LONG AS THEIR BEHAVIOR ISN’T UNETHICAL OR ABUSIVE AND THEIR VALUE OUTWEIGHS THE TOLL THEIR BEHAVIOR TAKES ON MANAGEMENT, COLLEAGUES, AND TEAMS.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On managing a board of directors
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Patrick Pichette: “Bill saw all the chess pieces all the time, because he had the luxury of not being on the board.”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TOP “BILLISMS”
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bill often had a unique way of telling you that he loved you. These are his top ten favorites, as recalled by his Columbia friend and teammate Ted Gregory. &lt;strong&gt;They were printed on the back page of the program given to guests at Bill’s memorial service.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“That’s the sound of your head coming out of your ass.”&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“Don’t fuck it up.”&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;“You’re so fucked up you make me look good.”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On High performers
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In fact, it is often the highest-performing people who feel the most alone. They usually have more interdependent relationships but feel more independent and separate from others&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On coaching the top
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“I don’t take cash, I don’t take stock, and I don’t take shit.”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/trillion-dollar-coach/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/trillion-dollar-coach/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
        <category>Personal-Growth</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The more something threatens your identity, the more you will avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Mark Manson, this self-help book actually paints a subtly different story than one would expect from the title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Manson draws from his life experiences to highlight the fact that we should care a little less about the small things but give it our all to things that really matter. The life-blogger truly dissects the entire positivity conundrum to teach us the fact that it is okay to sometimes not be okay. He drives the point home that if you’re worrying too much about small things in life that you don’t really have too much going on in your own life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manson makes up a law called the Manson’s Law of Avoidance that states the simple fact that the more something threatens your identity, the more you will avoid it. This simple fact makes sense on reading, but actually thinking about it retroactively makes so much sense and truly was the highlight from this book for me. Moreover, his words on choosing a broader identity rather than a narrower one truly resonated with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manson’s replacement of the Inspiration →  Motivation → Desirable Action loop with Desirable Action → Inspiration → Motivation → Desirable Action also put the point forward that one must do something before seeing the smallest of results which will in turn drive inspiration and motivation. This simple fact of simply starting something off and then gaining inspirations from the results to continue and finish the task truly drive home the point that he borrows from Tim Ferriss of actually doing something first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I liked the part where he asks the reader to assume that everything that has happened to them is a result of their own actions and doings directly. It put some things in perspective for me that sometimes I may not always been the victim of the circumstance and there were ways for me to avoid getting into such situation or even if I did, at least learn to spot them earlier and act on them.
Another part I liked about the book, is the part where he describes absolute freedom to be utterly meaningless, since I have personally seen myself fill up time with useless unproductive tasks whenever I had the time and the freedom. The following quote put some things in sense for me in the longer run, and I will definitely try to keep in mind as I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the only way to achieve meaning and a sense of importance in one’s life is through a rejection of alternatives, a narrowing of freedom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this humor packed, occasionally sarcastic 50 thousand page word book was worth the read and if I’m going to be completely honest I extremely liked certain parts of the book while other parts of the book were just there for me, or maybe a little irrelevant at this stage in life for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/subtle-art/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/subtle-art/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        <category>Motivational</category>
        
        <category>Personal-Growth</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have not read many books, and out of the handful only a few have managed to keep me reading for 4 days straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by Wall Street Journalist John Carreyrou, Bad Blood details the meteoric rise and the equally meteoric demise of Theranos, the bio-medical tech firm that promised to revolutionize the blood testing industry forever. If you are not familiar with the story of Theranos, here’s the short version: Founded in 2003 by a Stanford dropout when she was just 19, Theranos promised to reduce the volume required for blood tests to just a single drop pricked from the finger. In the years that followed, controlled by founder Elizabeth Holmes, the company went on to become a $10 billion dollar behemoth with partnerships with Walgreens among others. As for Elizabeth herself in 2015, she went on to be featured on the covers of &lt;i&gt;Forbes&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Fortune&lt;/i&gt; magazine after being named the youngest and wealthiest self-made female billionaire in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2013, Theranos was valued at $10 billion dollars but their technology never worked, and by the following year news broke out of the same. Elizabeth along with her then boyfriend/business partner Ramesh “Sunny” Balwani are now facing multiple lawsuits in federal court and were indicted in June 2018 for multiple wire-fraud charges even after relinquishing control of the company which was shut down soon after in August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The investors along with the public had no idea of Theranos’ deception until Carreyrou published his investigative report in the Journal. The book offers a remarkable inside look inside the company that was once Silicon Valley’s darling but is now as deep sunken as the Titanic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a Steve Jobs like “Reality Distortion Field” around her, Elizabeth had the ability to influence and win over people. She was so influential and conniving that she had managed to avoid an ambush by her own board members to fire her by convincing them using the right combination of “contrition and charm” as Carreyrou describes it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the details in the book are totally insane. During a demo to an investor, Theranos would slow the progress bar on the device to a crawl if the device would encounter an error. During this time, the investor would leave only for an engineer to take out the sample from the device and test in the commercial medical devices available on the market. After a few hours the relevant party would receive the results in the mail to be none the wiser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as plans for Theranos devices to be put into Walgreens stores were taking shape, Elizabeth hid the progress of the project from the people at Walgreens invested in the project. Not only that, Sunny and Elizabeth ran the Theranos ship in tight control, so much so that they did not allow inter-team interactions and even monitored and reprimanded the employees for doing the same. The people at the company joked that the turnover rate was so high that you would never be bored at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to John, who blew the cover on this massive fraud. The bigger question? If someone like Elizabeth Holmes could pull off such an elaborate scheme, one that ultimately put patient’s lives at risk, how do we prevent it in the future? A riveting page-turner, and a must-read for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book and the story it described of Silicon Valley made me a wee bit wary of my own prospects there. It raises some serious ethical questions, but it is ultimately a thriller with a tragic ending. It’s a fun read full of bizarre details that will make you gasp out loud. The story almost feels too ridiculous to be real at points (no wonder Hollywood is already planning to turn it into a movie bringing Jennifer Lawrence out of her one year acting hiatus).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/bad-blood/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bad-blood/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Non-fiction</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
        <category>Science</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
